Mikhail Romanenko (he/him)

San Jose, CA

Email: romanenkomv24@gmail.com

Mobile: 908-800-4506

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rmikhail/

U.S. Green Card holder | Fully Vaccinated

Summary:

Self-driven Python SDET with extensive practice in software quality assurance and overall testing. Big picture understanding, detail-focused, and reliable Engineer with over 6+ years of hands-on experience (3+ years in Fortune 500) in testing large-scale customer-facing products. API backend/platform master of automation with Python and requests library. Understating of Big O Notation, data structures and algorithms. Extensive knowledge in both automated and manual testing of web applications, services, and complex APIs. Committed to the highest product quality and project success. Leader and team player with a can-do attitude who can take on challenges.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

SDET

The Intercontinental Exchange (ICE: NYSE), El Segundo, CA > Remote 2020 – Present

- Designed, developed and managed testing frameworks from scratch for 3 integration teams using Python. Set up Docker and containerized test environments, spin up an Amazon EC2 (Linux). Defined declarative pipelines with Jenkins to create Continuous Integration (CI) for Sanity and Regression tests, overall release pipeline. Worked closely with SRE/DevOps.
- Signed off the main new feature being developed since Q1 2021 with targeted release on Feb 22 that is consumed by 3 major products in the company. Defined test strategies, performed White/Grey/Black box, automated API, verification JSON responses, database validation, unit, UI, security and other functional and non-functional tests. Maintained regression and smoke test suites. Signed off on product release.
- Owned the whole testing process for the entire containerization of core web services which
 are consumed by 2 major products in the company. Involving moving over 30 existing web
 services to Docker containers. Revisioned, tested and automated tests for new APIs.
- Managed offshore automation team of 5. Interviewed, mentored, assigned tasks, followed up, performed code review for individual contributions (PRs, comments, etc).
- Involved in various meetings with business analysts, product managers and developers, daily standup, grooming, sprint retrospective, reviews, demos and other.

Software Test Engineer

Google (via eTouch Systems), Mountain View, CA

10/2017 - 02/2020

- Orchestrated and participated in a complete QA process (bi-weekly sprints with daily standups), improving test coverage, feature requests, maintenance (build acceptance, regression) and support for one of the top Google Application - Web, Android and iOS.
- Managed resources and planned test coverage in between teams in the General Availability enterprise launch from Alpha stage, which combines work of 20+ teams across Google.
 Cloud telephony solution for major world known companies like Nielsen, Dow Jones, the City of Edmonton in Canada, ZPG in the UK, Portland State University, and more.
- With Python automated presubmit, CUJ and dogfood tests (release acceptance) for Web and Android clients using UIAutomator and Copycat (Google internal product) and Git for CI.
- Led a remote team of 3 QA engineers in Hyderabad, India. My responsibilities were: assigning tasks, following up with their progress, planning test coverage and providing technical guidance when needed.
- Participated in Google+ API reliability shutdown sprint, organized the testing process and distributed test suites to the QAs (including the team of my own in India).

Software QA Engineer

FUJISOFT America Inc., San Mateo, CA

04/2017 - 10/2017

- Developed robust automation tests for regression and build acceptance suites using Kyocera testing framework utilizing knowledge of Python and Selenium.
- Utilized Page Object model to improve reliability and effectiveness of the automated testing.
- Tested AI (robotics) using Python and RViz (visualizer application) on a real robot.
- Created and executed test cases, test suites, test strategies of native and hybrid apps for the major Japanese mobile manufacturer Kyocera in accordance with BRD and FSD.
- Collected and analyzed logs, measured RF performance using QXDM for At&T and Sprint on-field tests.
- Tested the company's website using knowledge of HTML and CSS, troubleshoot and debugged common issues.

Software QA Engineer

MechCAD Software LLC, Tamarac, FL

09/2014 - 02/2017

- Tested Web applications (User interface API with Postman).
- Tested native mobile application for iOS and Android mobile platforms.
- Conducted usability, functionality, compatibility, GUI, build acceptance and regression.
- Executed automated testing projects using Selenium WebDriver, JUnit.
- Utilized FireBug and Firepath to identify locators for Web Elements.
- Used ADB commands to install and remove apps, collect logs, screenshot, video capture.
- Created and executed test cases and test strategies for all components of the application.

Technical Skills:

Languages: Python, HTML, CSS, .NET, Groovy

API: RESTful API, Python (requests), Postman, JSON, SOAP, Swagger

Test: Selenium WebDriver, PyTest, Grid

Tools: Kibana, Android SDK (ADB), Chrome Developer Tool, JMeter, Xcode, Regex

Platforms: Linux/UNIX, macOS, Mobile (Android, iOS), AWS, EC2, VPC, ECS, S3

Tracking: JIRA, Zephyr, Buganiser, Confluence, Bugzilla

Databas: Redis, PostgreSQL, MySQL Model: Agile: Scrum, Kanban. Waterfall VE: Docker, Conda, Miniconda, Pyenv

CI/VC Git/GitHub (https://github.com/MikeRomanenko/), Jenkins, Azure TFS, Terraform

Education:

06/14 PhD in Engineering (on hold), Institute of Engineering Systems and Power, Krasnoyarsk State Agrarian University

06/12 MS, Electrical Engineering, Krasnoyarsk State Agrarian University